

SUMMARY

I provide meaning and context to data so that people can make informed decisions that improve the business every day.

I have 8 years experience working as a Data Scientist, both as team and technical lead, and an educational background in Computer Science, Applied Mathematics and Business. In my career I've worked closely with Marketing teams in B2B and B2C companies from the early stages of their measurement strategy, supporting the team to achieve fast growth.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2012 - present DATA SCIENCE LEAD - SHOPIFY

For over four years I was leading the team responsible for Marketing Analytics. During that period we rebuilt our entire data warehouse. As part of the Marketing data pipeline, we collect every click on our website through Kafka events and we extract data from external APIs, which are cleaned and transformed to build our data models using Spark. They are loaded to Presto and Redshift and we create our reports and dashboards in Tableau and Mode Analytics.

Since July/2017, I've switched to a technical lead role to improve the data science discipline across several teams. I help share the knowledge between teams, identify our main challenges and areas for improvement, define standards, and create tools to optimize how we work.

2010 - 2012 MARKETING INTELLIGENCE MANAGER - DAFITI

My role at Dafiti involved leading a team to provide tracking, analytics, and reporting support to the company's marketing efforts in Brazil, Argentina, Chile, Colombia and Mexico.

I was responsible for defining the whole tracking strategy to measure marketing campaigns and customer behavior, from the tools and tracking code implemented on the site to the URL parameters used by each channel, assuring the consistency and reliability of the data collected.

I analyzed and reported on marketing campaigns across multiple channels, consolidating data from internal and external sources to optimize the results.

SKILLS

Technical

- SOL
- Data Warehousing
- ETL
- Python
- PySpark
- Google APIs
- Data visualization
- Tableau
- HTML / CSS
- Liquid language
- JavaScript

Business & Personal

- Presentation
- Digital Analytics
- · Online Marketing
- Google Analytics
- Office suite

Languages

- Portuguese
- English

2 Page		Vanessa Sabino
2010	SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - BUSCAPÉ	
	Development of new features for BuscaPé using Java.	
2009	SYSTEM ANALYST - UOL	
	Development of the billing platform using Java.	
2004	LEAD MOBILE PROGRAMMER - DEVWORKS	
	Development of games for mobile phones using JME.	
2000 - 2003	SYSTEM ANALYST - ACCENTURE	

Consulting projects for several clients using a variety of technologies.

EDUCATION

2011	Ms. Computer Science Universidade de São Paulo
2006	Bs. Computational and Applied Mathematics Universidade de São Paulo
2001	Ba. Business Administration Fundação Getúlio Vargas
Online	University of British Columbia
Online	Coursera Introduction to Data Science Computing for Data Analysis

Web Intelligence and Big Data

Model Thinking